# **HOWARD LUAN**

Howard.Luan@dal.ca | (902) 981-8090 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/howardluan/

### **SUMMARY**

Knowledgeable and professional graduates in UI/UX Design and Web Development, technical support. Planned and created a variety of user documentation, including usability test guides, solving technical issues guides and received compliments by the peers. Performed technology upgrades for department resulted in one week ahead of planned schedule. More than 1 year experience explaining code concepts and algorithms for kids while maintaining their interest in coding. Highly efficient, attention to details with strong problem-solving, customer service and communication skills.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Computer Science, Co-op Education**

September 2018 – August 2022

## Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia

- Minor in Innovation and Entrepreneurship
- Certificate in Communication Technologies & Cyber Security
- International Learning Experiences Exchange student at University of Leeds in Fall 2019/2020

## **EXPERIENCE**

### **Program Facilitator**

January 2021 – Present

## **Code Ninjas Halifax**

- Explained JavaScript, Lua, C# code concepts and algorithms to kids, from six to fourteen, helping them understand the concepts better and solve their problems in their games.
- Led different types of camps, such as Roblox, Scratch, YouTube. Tasks including planning the curriculum, presenting, explaining, and helping participants with their content. Resulted in the increasing of returning kids to the programs.
- Created a Unity game used for promotions purpose and entertainment for kids, based on pre-developed characters and functions, as a motivation for kids to learn more and enjoy their time in the class.
- Greeted and checked in kids to the class, provided customer service to parents and introduced the program to first-time parents and kids. Resulted in boosting the sign-up rate for the organization.

#### **Technical Operational Assistant**

January 2022 – March 2022

#### **Dalhousie University - ISWEP**

- Created formal troubleshooting guide for common issues experienced by staff and frequently asked
  questions document for internal staff. Received compliments from supervisors and colleagues for the
  detailed and format.
- Planned, installed, upgraded, tested technology equipment for staff, including laptops, printer, docking station, cable organization. Completed the implementation ahead of schedule by one week.
- Provided technical support for staff having issues with new equipment, including software, hardware, cables, and docks. Received compliments from directors and employees for the knowledge and patience in solving technical issues.

myDal User Experience Coordinator

September 2021 – December 2021

**Dalhousie University** 

- Performed, reviewed, and reported on the usability of the internal department site and provided recommendation to improve the user experience for employees. Resulted in the implementation of the recommended report.
- Planned, drafted, and created user documentation for staff to perform usability testing for their site. Document included recruiting participants, scripting for a usability test, what to perform during usability test. Accepted by supervisor and later distributed for internal use.
- Reviewed, summarized, and reported on various usability testing tools and provided recommendation to the organization. Saved the subscription fees on usability testing tools.

### **User-requirement analyst**

June 2020 – August 2020

### **Everybyte Digital Products Co-op**

- Participated in a team with four other members to create a prototype for a system that hires and manages Teaching Assistant at Dalhousie University.
- Prepared and interviewed with CBC, SimplyCast, Dalhousie Faculty of Computer Science to understand user requirements and provide a solution.
- Meetings every two days to discuss the project through Microsoft Teams while studying two courses remotely.
- Received the most vote for the best idea from fellow members in the company.

# **SKILLS**

| <b>Language</b>       |                           |                        |                        |                      |
|-----------------------|---------------------------|------------------------|------------------------|----------------------|
| English               | Vietnamese                | Chinese                |                        |                      |
| <b>★★★★☆</b>          | ****                      | ★★★☆☆                  |                        |                      |
| <b>Technical</b>      |                           |                        |                        |                      |
| HTML & CSS<br>★★★☆    | JavaScript & ReactJS ★★★☆ | Cloud Computing ★★★☆   | UI & UX Design<br>★★★☆ | Design Thinking ★★★☆ |
| Database System  ★★☆☆ | PHP<br>★★★☆☆              | Network Computing ★★★☆ | Android Studio ★★☆☆    | Java<br>★★★☆☆        |
| <b>Interpersonal</b>  |                           |                        |                        |                      |
| Problem Solving ★★★★  | Customer Service ★★★☆     | Organization<br>★★★☆   | Communication ★★★☆     | Adaptability<br>★★★★ |

## **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

# Dalhousie Technology Innovation class project

May 2021 – July 2021

- Leader of the team of four students in the project, discussed and assigned tasks using Agile Scrum development method via Asana.
- Organized meetings with team members using Microsoft Teams to follow-up the progress of the project and discuss changes in the project.
- Collaborated and implemented a prototype of the project via Git Version Control.

#### **Picturegram**

**Project FishShip** 

September 2020 - December 2020

### Dalhousie Server-side scripting class project

- Integrated the database to extract data and display data dynamically based on the database using PHP and MySQL commands.
- Created the front-end of the website using HTML and Bootstrap.
- Created a database using phpMyAdmin and MySQL.